(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E15 -= Slice.of.Life.II =- Subripped by zerox
-还给我 -没门
- Give it back. - No way.
妈妈，她是个疯婆子
Look out, Mom, she's a wild woman.
你两住手
Okay, stop it. Both of you.
这个周末爸爸很忙，我怎么说了？
Now, what did I tell you about disturbing your father this weekend?
总的来说是别打扰他
Well, in a nutshell, you told us not to.
如果打扰他呢？
And if you did?
你会把我们吊起来关在地下室
You'd hang us by our thumbs in the basement.
那就对了，拿绳子来
That's right. Now, get me the rope.
爸爸，请听我解释.
Dad, I'm confident when you hear my story...
对不起，我错了
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
爸爸，我叫了本安静一点 可是他就是不听话
Dad, I tried to tell Ben to be quiet, but did he listen? No, he persisted...
对不起，我错了
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
亲爱的，写得怎样了？
How's the paper coming, honey?
我同意你的说法 别着急，你会写完的
I agree completely, but don't worry, you'll get it done.
鸡蛋要怎么煮？
Now, how do you want your eggs?
不好意思，没有辣酱了
I'm sorry, I think we're out of Tabasco.
我找些别的酱吧，拿着
I'll find some. I'll find some. Here, take this.
这些先吃着，其余的马上就好
This'll get you started, and I'll bring the rest out in a minute.
妈妈，地板打蜡了？
Mom, did you just wax this floor?
怪不得滑起来特别快
Because I picked up an incredible amount of speed...
对不起，我错了
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
杰森，来，回去工作 我来料理
Here. Now, Jason, go back to work. I'll take care of it.
-妈妈，这是意外 -麦克，这是最后通牒
- Mom, it was an accident, I swear. - Mike, this is your last warning.
若再在家里溜冰.
If we catch you skateboarding in the house again...
不许你接电话，不许听音响.
you'll lose your phone privileges, your stereo...
还有两个月不给钱你
and your allowance for two months.
妈妈
Mom.
行了，行了
Okay.
-你好，里奇 -西弗太太
- Oh, hi, Richie. - Hi, Mrs. Seaver.
不是吧
Oh, no.
里奇，旧报纸昨天不是收过了吗？
Richie, didn't you collect for the paper yesterday?
这次不是为了公事
Oh, this isn't a professional visit, Mrs. Seaver.
我来是.
I'm here...
里奇，我说过在图书馆见面的
Richie, I told you to meet me at the library.
考虑到我俩之间关系的进展.
Well, I just thought, I mean, in light of our new relationship and all...
我来这做功课吧
that we could work here.
关系？
Relationship?
你们是？男女关系？
What are you guys now, like boyfriend and girlfriend?
进展如何？
Kind of going steady?
她没告诉你？我们结婚了
Didn't she tell you? Carol and I are married.
-什么？ -这是社会科的课题
- What? - It's a social studies project.
我们要制订夫妻的预算
Yeah, we have to work out a budget for a married couple.
是模拟夫妻
A simulated married couple.
你们散发出洋溢的爱
Come on, guys, I can feel the love in this room.
你们是如何走在一起的？
So, what brought you two kids together, anyway?
命运的安排
Destiny.
还有我贿赂了全班的男同学.
And the fact that I paid off all the other guys in class...
要他们不要选你
so they wouldn't pick you.
什么？里奇？你买下了我？
What? Richie, you bought me?
是的
Yeah.
也许这方式比较老套
I guess I'm just old-fashioned that way.
够了!我不要和你做课题，出去!
That's it. I am not doing this project with you. Now, out!
星期一不交，我们会不及格
If we don't turn the paper in Monday, we get an F.
我可以遇见报纸的头条.. “凯罗.西弗不及格，举国震惊”
I can see the headlines now: "Carol Seaver gets an F. Nation in shock.
“总统结束休假回白宫”
"President to fly back from Santa Barbara."
麦克
Mike.
里奇，算了，我们还是做功课吧
Come on, Richie, let's get this over with.
亲爱的，随时恭候
Ready when you are, dear.
-他们真可爱.. -闭嘴
- Isn't that cute... - Not another word.
Hey.
谢谢，亲爱的 请放在桌子上
Thanks, honey. Just set it on the desk there, please.
好的
Okay, sure.
杰森，休息一下吧
Listen, Jason. Why don't you take a break?
-咱闲聊闲聊 -不行
- We could have a little chat. - I can't, honey.
我要把它写完
I've really got to get this done.
Oh.
要不暂停一阵子，咱聊聊.
But how about a short break, and then we could talk...
麦姬，不行，我一定要完成
Maggie, no, I've really got to finish up here.
-聊两句也不行..？ -麦姬
- But don't you think a little conversation... - Maggie.
-你到底要聊什么？ -我？
- What do you want to talk about? - Who? Me?
-没什么 -那好
- Oh, nothing. - Okay.
瞧孩子们的照片
Gosh, look at this picture of the kids.
麦克当时才8岁，瞧他的乖样
Mike must have been about eight years old. Wasn't he a cutie-pie?
我记得二年级老师称他为“小魔鬼”
I believe the word his second grade teacher used was "devil boy."
可她住院后，麦克送她卡片了
Oh, come on, he sent her a card in the hospital.
是啊
Yeah.
瞧凯罗，学东西一直都这么快
Oh, and look at Carol. She was always such a quick learner.
所以才戴上这么一副大眼镜
Yeah. That's why she's got alphabet soup up her nose.
还有本，多么无忧无虑
Yeah, little Ben. He was always such a happy baby.
每次弄湿尿布都哈哈大笑
Yeah. I remember the way he used to laugh every time he'd fill a diaper.
是啊
Yeah.
有一次我去了艾伦家.
You know, I was over at Ellen Harper's the other day...
看到她们家杰西卡在学走路
and I saw Jessica take her first steps.
太有意思了
It was so exciting.
是很有意思，那孩子都17岁了
I would think so. The girl's 17.
-那是马乔里 -是的，马乔里
- You're thinking of Marjorie. - Marjorie, yeah.
杰森，可惜你不在场.
Anyway, Jason, you should've seen it.
杰西卡那两条胖胖的小腿.
Jessica stood up on her chubby little legs...
摇摇晃晃走了3步.
and took three chubby little steps...
然后胖胖的脸着地了
and then fell on her chubby little face.
杰森，想过再要一个孩子吗？
Jason, do you ever think about having another child?
想过
Oh, yes, I do, Maggie.
有时候还梦见过呢
Sometimes I even dream about it.
-是吗？ -结果被吓醒了
- You do? - And then I wake up screaming.
麦姬，我了解你的心情
Maggie, I know what you're going through.
-是吗？ -是的，你这种年龄的妇女.
- You do? - Yes. It's a syndrome...
常常会有想再生一个孩子的.
and it's very common among women your age...
这种综合症
who suddenly feel the urge to have one more baby.
有什么不好？
Well, what's wrong with that?
没什么，但你刚恢复工作.
Well, nothing, except you've just gone back to work...
而且家里要再加一个房间
and we'd have to add a room onto the house.
我们一家已经很完美了
Anyway, I thought we already had the family we wanted.
杰森，别单纯用理性来思考.
Come on, Jason, those are just rationalizations...
再感性地想想看
but stop and think about it a minute.
有真正的理由让我们 不能再要一个孩子吗？
Can you give me one real reason why we shouldn't have another child?
等等
Wait here.
行，接下来检查基本费用.
Okay, next we have to go over the basic home expenses...
水电煤气，暖气费.
water, heat, gas, electric...
-你还在吗？ -致死不渝
- Are you with me? - Till death do us part.
你们俩刚蜜月归来？
Hey, I haven't seen you crazy kids since you got back from the honeymoon.
里奇，带着宠物.
Hey, Richie, did you have any trouble finding a hotel...
找酒店有困难吗？
that would take pets?
麦克
Mike.
没关系，我来处理
No, it's all right, Carol, I'll handle this.
麦克
Mike...
你要收回刚才的话
I'll have to ask you to take that back.
里奇，别误会了，凯罗可是个好东西
No, no, Richie, don't get me wrong. I mean, Carol's a great catch.
清理清理，去了骨头就会很好吃
And as soon as she's cleaned, scaled and deboned, she's fine.
麦克，我警告你
And now I'm warning you, Mike.
谁也不能侮辱我的模拟太太
Nobody talks to my simulated wife like that.
模拟兴否，我都爱她
Simulated or not, I love her.
你闯祸了!
Oh, now see what you done?
亲爱的，别哭，老公来了
Honey, don't cry. Your Richie's coming.
你疯了？妈妈禁止你溜冰
What, are you crazy? Mom told you not to do that.
怎样？要告发我？
What are you gonna do? Tell on me?
你以为我不敢？
I'm kicking it around.
你怎么证明我在溜冰？
How you gonna prove it?
找证据还真不容易
Oh, I don't think evidence will be such a problem.
本，本，本.
Ben, Ben, Ben.
我还能对你说什么呢？
What can I say about you that hasn't already been said?
可以说我快要发财了
That I'm about to become a rich man.
本，替我顶罪
Look, Ben, you got to take the rap for me here.
你是初犯
Now, you're a first-time offender.
爸妈只会要你赔偿玻璃的费用
Mom and Dad'll only make you pay for the window...
回头我还给你
and I'll pay you back for that.
-另加30块 -30块？
- That, plus $30. - $30?
手续费
Overhead.
-本，我没那么多钱 -那就对不起了
- Ben, I don't have that kind of money. - I'm sorry to hear that, Mike.
外面怎么了？
Hey, what's going on in there?
本，我是你哥哥，我爱你
Ben, you're my brother. I love you.
好吧，我可以给你点优惠
Okay, Mike, I'm gonna cut you some slack here.
其实钱并不重要，对不？
Because, after all, money isn't that important, is it, Mike?
对，对
No. No.
重要的是一个人.
What's more important is what one human being can do...
帮忙另一个人
for another human being.
对，对
Right, right.
所以这个周末你要成为我的仆人
That's why I'd like you to be my personal servant for the weekend.
你这!
What? You little...
干嘛这么吵..谁干的？
What was that noise in... Hey, who did this?
溜冰板？
Is that a skateboard?
好吧，我依你
Okay, I'll do it.
妈妈，爸爸，也许你们不相信.
Mom, Dad, I know this is unbelievable, but...
我拿了麦克的溜冰板玩 结果飞出去了
I was fooling around on Mike's skateboard, and the thing went flying.
-本，是你？ -是的，对不起
- You did this, Ben? - Yeah. And I'm really, really sorry.
对不起也没用 这要从你的零花钱里面扣
Well, sorry just isn't good enough, Ben. That's gonna come out of your allowance.
若是再在家里溜冰.
And if we ever catch you skateboarding in the house again...
我要你吃不了，兜着走!
you're gonna discover the true meaning of the word "sorry."
我去收拾掉碎玻璃
Well, I'd better clean up that broken glass.
老弟，你处理得条条是道
All right, little bro. We handled that pretty well.
慢着
Freeze, sleaze.
-什么？ -我们之前好像有协议
- What? - I believe we had a little arrangement.
等等，刚才只是说笑.
Wait a minute, Ben, you didn't take that little joke...
仆人的事，你可别当真
about the servant business seriously, did you?
妈妈
Oh, Mom.
我..会服侍你
I ought to... pamper you silly.
我算好了，没超出预算
I have my figures ready. We're still way under budget.
里奇，消遣这一项花费是0
Richie, you've got $0 down for entertainment.
我们在家里消遣就好了
I kind of figured we'd have home entertainment.
生11个孩子怎么样？
How do you think we got 11 children?
11个孩子？
Eleven children?
荒谬!
I don't believe it.
你收买了我 然后把我当作下蛋的母鸡
I mean, first you buy me, and then you turn me into a baby machine.
这不是我们的共同愿、望吗？
I thought that's what we both wanted.
够了，我的愿、望是和你分居
That's it. I'll tell you what I want. I want a separation.
把预算分成两份
We're dividing the budget into two separate households.
-那孩子呢？ -孩子都归你
- What about the kids? - You keep the kids.
你找我的律师谈吧
You'll be hearing from my attorney.
生气时仍旧迷人
God, she's cute when she's angry.
你的三明治
Your sandwich.
天哪，这是什么？
Oh, dear. What do I see here?
照你的吩咐，3份花生酱.
Ben, it's just like you ordered, three parts peanut butter...
一份蜜饯，还有奶油.
one part marshmallow, a dollop of cream cheese...
最后加一粒半葡萄干
topped with one and a half raisins.
但我没说过要面包皮
Yes, but I still see a speck of crust.
我最讨厌面包皮了
You know my feelings about crust.
好吧，我去弄掉
Okay, I'll cut it off.
麦克，这样不行
No, Michael, that just won't do.
依我看来，再弄一份吧
In the state I'm in, I'll need an all-new another sandwich.
再弄一份？
A new sandwich?
我要香肠，奶酪再加法国芥末
I see salami and cheese, and a tangy French mustard.
-你，你.. -妈妈.
- I ought to... - Oh, Mom.
-好吧，好吧.. -好什么？
- Okay, okay. - "Okay, okay," what?
大老爷
Okay, okay, Lord Ben.
-可以坐一会儿吗？ -可以
- Mind if I sit here a second? - Sure, fine, sit.
-我一直在想.. -想吧
- You know, I've been thinking... - Sure, fine, think.
想起斯哥姆湖畔的别墅
About that summer home on Squam Lake...
我们就暂停分期付款吧
you know, maybe we should hold off putting down that deposit.
好的，暂停分期付款
Sure, fine, hold off.
暑假不去那里度假.
Because if we stay home this summer...
就能在这添一个房间了
maybe we could add that new room onto the house.
好的，添一个房间
Sure, fine, add a room.
添房间是因为.
I was thinking we'd need an addition because...
我也许怀孕了
I might be having a baby.
好的，怀孕吧
Sure, fine, have a baby.
-怀孕？ -还不确定
- A baby? - Now, I'm not sure yet.
医生两点会打电话来告知结果
The doctor has to call back at 2:00 with the test results.
怀孕？
A baby?
杰森，其实早就想告诉你了.
Jason, I didn't tell you sooner because I knew...
但是你要集中精神写文章，只是.
you needed to concentrate on your article, but then...
我等电话越等越急.
I got so nervous waiting for the doctor's call...
麦姬，这意味着什么？
Maggie, do you know what this means?
我们又有个孩子了!
It means we're having a baby.
-你开心？ -开心？
- You mean you're glad? - Glad?
我的心情怎能用“开心”来形容？
Maggie, "glad" doesn't begin to describe how I feel.
我感到“很开心”!
I feel... really glad!
我还以为你不想要孩子了
But Jason, I thought you didn't want to have another child.
那是在没有怀孕的前提下
Well, that was before I got to know him.
孩子来得真不是时候
Oh, honey, it's so weird that this should happen now...
我刚刚恢复工作
just when I started back to work.
我准备不去上班，留下来当妈妈
I guess I'II... Well, I guess I'll just have to quit my job to be a mommy.
不，现在情况完全不同了
No. No, no. Don't you see? It's different this time, Maggie.
我已经在家了，我来带孩子吧
I'm already home. I'll be the mommy.
-那就不能用人奶喂养了 -是的
- I guess that rules out breastfeeding. - No... Yeah.
其余的我都能胜任
But I can do everything else.
喂牛奶，换尿布，洗澡什么的
I can bathe him, I can burp him, I can change him.
指导孩子的人生路
I'll guide his destiny.
我的机会来了
This is my chance.
可以补偿我错过这3个孩子的事情
This is my chance to recapture all the things I've missed with the other kids.
-不怕孩子们整天哭？ -我把耳朵塞起来
- Like their crying all day long? - I'll wear earplugs.
-堆积如山的尿布.. -我把鼻子塞起来
- Like tons of dirty diapers? - I'll wear nose plugs.
凌晨3点喂奶？
3:00 a.m. Feedings?
麦姬，若你是如此的消极.
Maggie, if you're gonna have a negative attitude about this...
那我来带孩子是好事
it's a good thing I'm raising this kid.
既然你这么想，自己去生一个吧
Well, if that's the way you feel about it, have your own darn baby.
你以为我不想？
I could if I wanted to.
麦姬.
Maggie...
我希望有你的孩子
I want to have your baby.
杰森，你真是太好了
Oh, Jason, that's sweet.
孩子啊，孩子.
Baby, baby, baby, baby
凯罗.
Hi, Carol.
-怎样了？ -很好，你呢？
- How's it going? - Fine. How are things with you?
凯罗，你回来吧 我的预算不够开销
Carol, you gotta come back. I can't make it alone on my budget.
我和你的钱是一样多的
Hey, you've got just as much money as I do.
我有11个孩子
I've got all 11 kids.
我们住破棚子，每天吃饲料
We live in a shack. All we have to eat is fish food.
里奇，我看你是在想入非非了
Richie, I think you're getting a little carried away here.
我花了60块，怎能不想入非非？
Hey, I think I'm entitled to get a little carried away for my $60.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
买你这个搭档的花费
Well, that's what I had to pay to get you as a partner.
里奇，你疯了，这可不是个小数目
But, Richie, that's crazy. I mean, that's a lot of money.
凯罗，金钱不代表什么
Money isn't everything, Carol.
需要的话，600块我也能拿出来
I would've paid $600 for you, if that's what it took.
这真是一句.
That's the sweetest...
最接近精神病的情话
and most borderline psychotic thing anyone's ever said to me.
我就是这样
Hey, that's just the kind of guy I am.
不过你还是不满足
But I guess that's not good enough for you.
里奇.
Look, Richie.
也许我们能破镜重圆.
Maybe we can arrange a simulated trial reconciliation...
直到星期一为止
until Monday.
凯罗，欢迎你回家
Carol, welcome home.
我去告诉孩子们
Wait till I tell the kids.
至高无上的本 兰波玩具的衣服烫好了
Your Rambo doll clothes are ready, your most exalted Ben.
麦克，我们很不满意
Oh, Michael, we are not pleased.
这条皱褶太难看了
Rambo's crease here looks terrible.
穿皱皱的裤子，又怎能保卫国土？
How's the man supposed to defend our country in wrinkled pants?
我的饼干好了，我要趁热吃
Oh, my cookies are ready, Michael. And I like them hot.
好的
Right.
换台，7频道
Channel 7, Mike.
我的饼干呢？我闻到焦味了
My cookies, Michael. I could swear I smell them burning.
好的
Right.
麦克，接电话
The phone, Michael.
这里是本.西弗大王的家
Seaver residence. Home of the Royal Ben...
喂，珍妮
Jennifer, hi.
珍妮？
Jennifer?
我吩咐过，不能接私人电话
I said, no personal calls.
本，是俏臀妹妹打来的
Ben, that was Wonderbuns.
俏臀妹妹？我是本
Hello, Wonderbuns? Big Ben here.
麦克没空.. 麦克，你在干什么？
Mike is not available... Mike, what do you think you're doing?
-我要造反 -麦克，不得无礼
- I'm revolting. - No argument there, Mike.
-你这小厮.. -我要告诉爸爸是你打破玻璃的
- Why, you little... - I'm gonna tell Dad you broke the window.
我要告发你敲诈勒索，你这小流氓
Well, I'm gonna tell Dad you're a blackmailer, you little gangster.
爸爸会把你关起来
Well, Dad's gonna ground you.
爸爸会把你关起来，还会用刑
Well, Dad's gonna ground you and spank you.
你们两个别吵
Hold it right there, you two.
你们真可爱，我来拍拍照
You boys look so cute, I gotta take your picture.
还记得你们小时候.
Hey, you remember when you guys were just little babies...
玩拍拍手吗？
how we used to play Pat A Cake?
-记得 -当时很好玩是吧
- Yeah. - That was big time fun.
现在玩玩怎样？
What do you say we play a quick game right now?
-好吧 -还是快点玩吧
- Yeah, that's good. - If I were you, I'd get in on this.
“拍拍手，拍拍手..”
"Pat a cake, pat a cake, baker's man
“我们都是好朋友”
"Bake me a cake as fast as you can"
孩子们，你们都要被关起来 释放日期另行通知
Boys, you're both grounded until further notice, okay?
来笑一个
Smile, come on.
“拍拍手..”
Pat a cake, pat a cake.
-完成了 -太好了
- I'm finished. - That's great, honey.
我就知道你能写完
I knew you'd finish your paper today.
不是论文完成，我集中不了精神
No, not my paper. I couldn't concentrate on my paper.
我说的是给孩子取名
- I have a list of baby names. - Oh.
这是我的首选，独特，上口.
Here's my first choice. This is distinctive, it's commanding...
还很贵气，“朱利叶斯”
it's noble. It's Julius.
朱利叶斯.西弗？
Julius Seaver?
还不赖吧？
Not bad, huh?
还有许多选择，以防万一
I got plenty more, just in case.
万一什么？
Just in case of what?
万一他是个喜剧演员
Well, just in case he turned out to be a comedian.
就叫做西西弗
Sid Seaver?
如果只是普通的美国公民
And if he were an all-American, everyday kid.
-就叫做比弗.西弗 -比弗.西弗
- Beaver Seaver. - Beaver Seaver.
杰森，万一是女儿呢？
Jason, what if he's a girl?
那我还得再想想
Uh-oh. I better get back to work.
要是个女儿，我会帮她取名为.
Jason, I was thinking that if it's a girl, that we could name her...
丽贝卡
Rebecca.
丽贝卡.西弗，好听，我喜欢
Rebecca Seaver. That's pretty. I like that.
-希望她长得像你 -我也是
- I hope she looks just like you. - Me, too.
要是她胸口长毛那就太滑稽了
Because she'd look kind of silly with a hairy chest.
-是医生打来的 -先别接
- That's him. - Don't answer it.
我们应该一起接
We've both got to be on the phone at the same time.
我到客厅去接，等等
I'll get the phone in the living room. Hold on.
-好，快 -好
- Okay, hurry. - Go.
喂，大夫
Hello? Yes, Doctor.
Uh-huh.
知道了
I see.
好
Yes.
谢谢你打过来
Well, thank you for calling, Doctor.
也许这样是最好的
Well, I guess it's all for the best.
我还没做好思想准备呢
I mean, I wasn't really ready to go through all that again.
而且要你抽出这么多时间.
And it wouldn't have been fair to ask you to take...
对你来说很不公平
so much time away from your practice. I mean, I guess...
也许时机真的不对
I guess it just isn't the time.
你真的想要一个孩子是吧？
You really wanted to have a baby, didn't you?
是的，我很想
Yeah. I guess I did.
我也是
Well, I did, too.
这是个坏消息，也是个好消息
I guess we could look at this as good news and bad news.
坏消息是暂时没有孩子
Bad news is that we're not going to have a baby right now.
好消息是我们还可以继续努力生孩子
And the good news is that we can keep trying to have a baby.
也许要花几个星期时间
Even if it takes weeks.
甚至几个月
Or months?
关键在于我们要坚持不懈
Yes, the important thing is that we keep at it.
我会尽我所能
Well, I'm willing to do my part.
好吧，废话休提，我们开始吧
All right, the party's over. Let's get to work.
本，把溜冰板给我
Ben, give me my skateboard.
先把我的内裤从屋顶上拿下来
Not until you get my underwear down from the roof.
写得真棒
Very impressive, honey.
甚至可以说是写得龙飞凤舞
I might even go so far as to say that your paper is brilliant.
继续说
Go so far, say it.
晚饭时庆祝一下
What do you say we celebrate over dinner?
好主意
Good idea.
-妈妈大人 -爸爸大人
- Yes, your Momness. - Yes, your Dadness.
两份普通三明治
We'll have two club sandwiches.
加蛋黄酱，要涂满一点
Just a hint of mayo, on whole-wheat toast.
不要面包皮，我们最恨面包皮了
Oh, and hold the crust. You know how we feel about crust.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01